<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Karina Ramos-Musalem</title>
    <link>https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://anakarinarm.github.io/images/icon_huc41dee5293dde66ff6df247b25160a6b_163860_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction among multiple canyons</title>
      <link>https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/multiple-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/multiple-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Submarine canyons are not isolated features; they occur one after the other along the continental shelves around the world. The influence that one canyon may have on the flow dynamics of an adjacent one is not clear. It might be tempting to assume that the first canyon or upstream canyon leads the dynamics, since water will go through it before passing to the downstream canyon. However, the role of the downstream canyon is not trivial as coastal-trapped waves are moving in the opposite direction to the shelf current in the case of upwelling canyons. This means that information is also being transmitted from the downstream canyon to the upstream one. This type of interaction has been observed in Barkley Canyon where shelf waves propagating northward can have a stronger effect on alongshore currents than the local wind. We are studying how submarine canyons interact dynamically using a physical model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;relevant-publications&#34;&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.library.ubc.ca/cIRcle/collections/ubctheses/24/items/1.0388506&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PhD Thesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transport through a submarine canyon</title>
      <link>https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/tracer-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anakarinarm.github.io/project/tracer-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Submarine canyons incise continental shelves all over the world. They are hot spots of biodiversity mainly because they act as conduits for biologically relevant tracers (such as nitrate, phosphate, etc.) by enhancing upwelling. I am studying the impact that submarine canyons have on the amount of tracers that is exchanged between the shelf and the deep ocean, and the spatial and temporal distribution of the upwelled tracer on the shelf. I use an idealized canyon bathymetry and the MIT general circulation model (MITgcm) to develop a scaling scheme for tracer transport onto the shelf given the incomming flow, geometric and geographic parameters of the canyon, tracer profile, and vertical diffusivity and viscosity within the canyon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;relevant-publications&#34;&gt;Relevant publications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramos‐Musalem, K., &amp;amp; Allen, S. E. (2020). The Impact of Initial Tracer Profile on the Exchange and On‐Shelf Distribution of Tracers Induced by a Submarine Canyon. Journal of Geophysical Research: Oceans, 125(3), e2019JC015785.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramos-Musalem, K., &amp;amp; Allen, S. E. (2019). The Impact of Locally Enhanced Vertical Diffusivity on the Cross-Shelf Transport of Tracers Induced by a Submarine Canyon. Journal of Physical Oceanography, 49(2), 561-584.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JPO-D-18-0174.1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;10.1175/JPO-D-18-0174.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
